<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <image>
    <url>https://ioletsgo.gay/Assets/they.png</url>
    <title>Favicon for ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <link>https://blog.ioletsgo.gay</link>
  </image>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content from blog.ioletsgo.gay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 08:28:51 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms, and how they shift our minds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 08:28:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I oftentimes hear phrases from boomers like &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Social Media is ROTTING Your Brain!&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, and, while they may not be able to explain the difference between a Pentium and a Ryzen, maybe they&amp;rsquo;re not absolutely braindead in their assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest To Learn Programming: Prerequisites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 22:12:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;banner-for-the-quest-to-learn-programming-prerequisitespostsprogrammingbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner for The Quest To Learn Programming: Prerequisites&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my knowledge in computers, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to really sit myself down and learn programming. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it was never out of me not trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by computers, some of my earliest memories involve loading an old Dell laptop with so many viruses it constituted as a threat to national security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give you the whole &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;in 1981 the IBM Personal Computer was invented&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; talk cause, while I think its important, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to parrot the entire history of the personal computer, UNIX systems, DOS, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want an interesting look into the history of computers, I would probably recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@ComputerChroniclesYT&#34;&gt;The Computer Chronicles&lt;/a&gt;, beautifully archived on Youtube by Danooct1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I see it, computers are relatively simple devices that are able to do a lot of complicated maths due to make interesting things happen. While I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to enter from the deep end using x86 Assembly off the bat, I&amp;rsquo;m an inquisitive mind and I have a tendency to ask a lot of questions that leads to &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Well, In x86 assembly...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, which can be both annoying and demotivating if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the necessary resources to ask and get answers for complicated questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;I don&#39;t want to be the type of person that doesn&#39;t understand why or how programming works&lt;/code&gt;, which is why I made an unusual purchase of a programming textbook&amp;ndash; Particularly, the C++ Programming Language 4th Edition Hard Cover by Bjarne Stroustrup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cover-of-the-c-programming-language-fourth-edition-textbookpostsprogrammingcppbookjpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/CPPBook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The cover of the C++ Programming Language Fourth Edition Textbook&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intended goal is to be able to record my journey of using this resource, possibly in hopes to encourage others who are in a very similar position to me, the massive textbook being a constant physical reminder and motivator for me to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s fucking learn I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confronting Y2K: The Forgotten war against the infamous computer bug</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 20:44:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;banner-for-confronting-y2k-the-forgotten-war-against-the-infamous-computer-bugpostsy2kbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner for Confronting Y2K: The forgotten war against the infamous computer bug&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its leap day (making this an excuse to publish this blogpost), which means some systems with refuse to work, and I think makes it more than an appropriate time to talk about the New Years Disaster that could&amp;rsquo;ve been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more, every year, You hear a growing narrative from younger individuals, whom I am a part of, who weren&amp;rsquo;t alive or weren&amp;rsquo;t in tech spaces at the time, where they largely disregard the threat that was y2k. Thomas from hachyderm.io said the following thing which led to me actually making this blogpost:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hachyderm.io/@thomasfuchs/111682921557572060&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/ThomasPost.png&#34; alt=&#34;lol at people trying to retcon history and pretend the Y2K bug wasn&amp;rsquo;t real. I literally worked for like a year from late 1998 to the end of 1999 to fix databases of utility companies and health systems to not, you know, completely and utterly fail come January 1st, 2000.&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of something I remembered from browsing the wayback machine. An archive of the Department Of Defense &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_assigned_/8_IPv4_address_blocks#List_of_assigned_/8_blocks_to_the_United_States_Department_of_Defense&#34;&gt;(cough cough)&lt;/a&gt; website which was a valuable source of information leading up to years about proactive and preventative measures to take towards minimizing the potential impacts of Y2K.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930051316/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/homepage.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the Confronting Y2K homepage&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it would be both interesting, funny, and appropriate to retrospectively browse this website with hindsight in mind to see how well this operation was towards preventing a potentially destructive bug, and maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll come out of it more understanding and appreciation for the hard work that prevented doomsday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-confronting-y2k-website&#34;&gt;ABOUT THE CONFRONTING Y2K WEBSITE:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first site I browsed to trying to get information was the &lt;code&gt;About Me&lt;/code&gt; page. Outside of browser compatibility information which dates the creation of the website to 1997, there isn&amp;rsquo;t anything of real note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email address dedicated to the technical design of the site is defunct, and the site functions more as a warning about the collection of data than it exists as an &amp;ldquo;About Me&amp;rdquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930140106fw_/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/misc_fabout.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/aboutme.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the About Us page for Confronting Y2K&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, A very minimal site with not a lot of information, the year of creation is something to take of note, as this site was made 2 years before 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-y2k&#34;&gt;What is Y2K?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the page &amp;ldquo;What is Y2K&amp;rdquo; is 5 sections divided into their own sub pages, being Background, Impact, The Challenge, Y2K History, and Key Y2K Dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Confronting Y2K website, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be talking about them under the same category.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930160440fw_/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/y2k_back.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/WIY2Kbackground.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the Background page from What Is Y2K&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Background webpage gives an overview about Y2K which falls in line with the modern census accurately. It describes it as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Y2K is shorthand for the potential of computer operating systems, software programs and microchips to malfunction on January 1, 2000.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Without being repaired or replaced, many of these information technology components may misread the century change as 1900 instead of 2000. Such an error can cause systems to provide inaccurate information or shut down all together.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site labeled Impact outlines a short list of potential harm that could fall due to Y2K, the infrastructure they outlined are very critical systems for modern human life, including &lt;code&gt;food supplies, water, power, and health care&lt;/code&gt;. Alongside this information, they outlined how Y2K could be potentially harmful for national security, for over &lt;code&gt;1.5 million computers and 28,000 computer systems&lt;/code&gt; could be impacted by an unfixed Y2K bug.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930160439fw_/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/y2k_impact.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/impact.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot from the Impact page&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, They do an excellent job on not overselling the potential impacts, while not underselling it entirely either. It isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;WE&amp;rsquo;RE ALL GONNA DIE&amp;rdquo; levels of urgency, but it&amp;rsquo;s more like &amp;ldquo;Yeah we&amp;rsquo;d be kinda fucked if we don&amp;rsquo;t do anything about it&amp;rdquo;, kind of a dramatic contrast between how Y2K was seen in the media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Challenge is a page about the potential hardships that can come from addressing this issue, and certification on what it means to properly and fully address the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is largely where I think it gets a little bit juicy, As a younger individual in tech, I always kind of assumed that &amp;ldquo;Y2K compliance&amp;rdquo; was a self described award, but reading this page helps me come to the understanding that Y2K compliance was an actual award ratified by a central governing body given to hardware, software, and microchips.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930160440fw_/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/y2k_chall.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/thechallenge.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot from the &amp;lsquo;The Challenge&amp;rsquo; webpage&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements to reach Y2K compliance is reported as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;y2k-compliant&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Y2K Compliant:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;When a piece of hardware, software, or a microchip is described as Y2K compliant, it means it is certified as being able continue working through the year 2000 date without any disruption or degradation in its performance. To earn this certification, a system must pass a five-step process being used both in government and throughout business and industry in the United States. These steps are: find, fix, test, verify and install.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this very interesting, as an individual who believed that Y2K compliance simply became a buzzword used by corporations to sell snakeoil alternatives, claiming they&amp;rsquo;re better by bandwagoning off of hysteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily disagree with the motion that snakeoil was sold under the claim of being Y2K compliant, it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit interesting to know that the term originates with legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;y2k-history&#34;&gt;Y2K History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could really give any important information, outside of linking the page alongside an image of the post, for it gives additional context as to the creation of Confronting Y2K.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20170930160439fw_/http://archive.defense.gov/specials/y2k/y2k_hist.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k/history.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot from the Y2K History section of the website&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Probably the funniest section has to be the uncertainty in the last sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;January 1, 2000 -- All systems go?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laptop Nerd Builds Her First Computer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 09:15:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;banner-for-first-computer-blog-postpostscomputerbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner for First Computer Blog Post&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had my own personal desktop, which may be surprising for those who know me as a tech nerd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous blog post about &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/&#34;&gt;Chairs, Carpal Tunnel Syndrome, and my acute obsession with ergonomics&lt;/a&gt;, You probably noticed the fact that, despite being a tech nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a full tower PC. You can see this as a continuation of that previous blogpost, as a whole load of stuff has changed since then. Honestly I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start&amp;hellip;
So I guess we start where we last left off, with the Desk and what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;audio&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-my-desk-with-a-bunch-of-audio-equipment-like-a-microphone-midi-keyboard-and-an-audio-interfacepostscomputermusic1png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/music1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of my desk, with a bunch of audio equipment like a microphone, midi keyboard, and an audio interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve posted I&amp;rsquo;ve completely overhauled my audio setup. You may not have been able to tell, but in the original setup, I had a Behringer U-Phoria UM2 audio interface that started to get really static-y in the XLR port, almost to the point where the microphone became unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-a-behringer-u-phoria-um2postscomputerimage_be_p0avv_um2_front_xlpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/Image_BE_P0AVV_UM2_Front_XL.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of a Behringer U-Phoria UM2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After believing that its the microphone (and breaking it, I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a project for a later date. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ioletsgo.gay/index.xml#feed&#34;&gt;If that sounds like fun, please subscribe to the RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;), I had to replace my mic (that I bought Used) with a brand new AT2020, and a BluCoil 48 V Portable USB Audio Interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-a-blucoil-48-v-portable-usb-audio-interfacepostscomputerblucoil-portable-usb-audio-interfacewebp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/Blucoil-Portable-USB-Audio-Interface.webp&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of a BluCoil 48 V Portable USB Audio Interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my reasoning for choosing this audio interface was the fact that I wanted something that worked, but also had knobs on the front (My autistic brain absolutely loves physical dials and analog audio controls. Also they look really cool.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headphones I daily drive are the Audio Technica ATH-M50xBT2, costing around 170 dollars on sale. I can highly recommend these headphones for a multitude of reasons, with the battery being an easy sell and the mobile app being a change of pace compared to similar high end devices that makes you feel like you need it to get the least out of your devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-the-audio-technica-ath-m50xbt2-limited-edition-deep-sea-bluepostscomputerath-m50xbt2png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/ATH-M50XBT2.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of the Audio Technica ATH-M50xBT2 Limited Edition Deep Sea Blue&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire purpose of this build was Flexibility. I never, at any point, wanted to feel like I was held back by my hardware choices. If I, say, wanted to make Youtube Videos, I&amp;rsquo;m totally capable of doing that with this audio setup. If I wanted to make music, I have my Midi Keyboard, I have my myriad of musical instruments, and you&amp;rsquo;d better believe I&amp;rsquo;ll be busting some tunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-actual-computer&#34;&gt;The Actual Computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably didn&amp;rsquo;t click on this blog post for audio nerd shit. You clicked on this blog for some old fashioned computer nerd shit. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able satisfy that need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-noir&#34;&gt;The Noir&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-the-zalman-z3-iceberg-computer-casepostscomputerz3-icebergpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/Z3-Iceberg.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of the Zalman Z3 Iceberg Computer Case&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a Zalman Iceberg computer case, it ensures that this AMD-based system gets plenty of air, creating the best possible environment for my Linux system to operate, and for a cheap price too.
I built her over the span of 3 months, with the best end-of-the-line AM4 hardware possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-pc-part-picker-list-showing-a-high-end-computer-fully-paid-for-going-slightly-over-1600-usdpostscomputerpcpartpickerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/computer/pcpartpicker.png&#34; alt=&#34;A PC part picker list showing a high end computer fully paid for going slightly over 1,600 USD&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She can run basically any software I toss at it. With 32 gigs of ram she&amp;rsquo;s an absolute beast that only the highest end of AAA games with absolutely abysmal optimizations could dream of filling, all while running at a low 40C and only going to high 50Cs under heavy loads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time building a computer was definitely&amp;hellip; Interesting. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I basically had the entire thing built that I had to use my background in tech support to deduce that I got a faulty motherboard (I went all-in on the fact that the computer booted ONCE with no stability issues, even under heavy CPU, GPU, and RAM loads. If anything crashed while it was booted I knew that it was something else.), so I had to get a replacement. While I was swapping all of the components, I accidentally bent one of the pins on my CPU. Just my luck. Luckily I have small steady hands so I was able to bend the pins back with relative ease.
I was too busy focusing on fixing shit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even think to document it.
Building a computer was definitely a unique experience, multiple points did i lose motivation and almost give up, but I knew that it would all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porting the original blogpost to the new blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this desktop for over 4 months, and its been going really smooth. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any real trouble with it and its given me a lot of freedom to do stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to do. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;d heavily recommend building a computer for anybody who is interested in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7, eWaste, and the modern day Malware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 05:33:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-banner-using-the-windows-7-desktop-backgroundpostswin7bannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;A banner using the Windows 7 Desktop background&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 7 is an operating system that runs near and dear to my heart. I do feel, however, computer landscapes have changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do admit that I have a little bit of nostalgia towards Windows 7, from the skeuomorphism of the calculator app, to the lovely blues and cyans that fill the Frutiger Aero aesthetic. I have fond(ish) memories of filling up my family computer with all different types of malware. Exploring all these interesting osbcure websites that I probably only saw through advertisements or heard through word of mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-screenshot-of-a-windows-7-desktop-taken-from-an-old-toshiba-laptoppostswin7win7desktoppng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/win7desktop.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of a Windows 7 desktop taken from an old Toshiba laptop&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 7 in my mind was the last era that we truly had &amp;ldquo;The Wild West&amp;rdquo; of the internet, and that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing, &lt;em&gt;nor would I say it&amp;rsquo;s a particularly great thing either&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way that I view how Windows 7 was utilized was in the types of malware or scareware people developed for it. Windows 7 was the first operating system for countless individuals, and was one of the widest used computers on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-look-at-some-statistics-yay&#34;&gt;Lets look at some statistics! Yay!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chart from Statcounter GlobalStats shows us a map of Operating System usage in the 2012 year, with Windows 7 staying solidly in the 49-52 percentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-chart-by-globalstatspostswin7globalstatschartpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/globalstatschart.png&#34; alt=&#34;a chart by Globalstats&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, we have an rough number of how many computers not only were running Windows 7, but also how many of them were connected online in 2012, and that&amp;rsquo;s only possible due to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carna_botnet&#34;&gt;Carna Botnet&lt;/a&gt;. The Carna botnet was a nonmalicious entity that recorded pings on unsecured routers online. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://darknetdiaries.com/episode/13/&#34;&gt;If you want to learn more information outside of broad strokes, may I recommend Jack Rhysider&amp;rsquo;s Darknet Diaries episode on the Carna Botnet?&lt;/a&gt;) All you really need to know about the Carna botnet for this post is that it recorded 1.3 billion active addresses and 729 million reported DNS records.Taking another statistic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statista.com/statistics/748551/worldwide-households-with-computer/&#34;&gt;Statistica.com&lt;/a&gt;, 41.4% of the worldwide population of 2012 had atleast one computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining all of these statistics mathmatically leads us with &lt;strong&gt;2,922,840,000&lt;/strong&gt; internet capable devices, or an estimated 4 computers per household, and &lt;strong&gt;1,640,882,376&lt;/strong&gt; household devices running Windows 7 in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-gif-demonstrating-the-online-activity-of-routers-impacted-by-the-carna-botnethttpsuploadwikimediaorgwikipediacommons11acarnabotnet_geovideo_lowresgif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/1a/Carnabotnet_geovideo_lowres.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A gif demonstrating the online activity of routers impacted by the Carna botnet&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech is naturally a wasteful industry, however, I think that we oftentimes overlook how truly wasteful we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten within the past 20 years. With constant innovation comes the creation of tech that just straight up &lt;em&gt;ISN&amp;rsquo;T&lt;/em&gt; built to last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caps burst, batteries leak, and my god, we&amp;rsquo;re even starting to experience PCB tracerot in older consoles. I would absolutely love to say that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a motive as to why this has been not only a consistent problem, but an escalating one at that. There&amp;rsquo;s a simple and easy truth as to why it seems to be that tech keeps getting more fragile in certain aspects as the technology gets better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-is-capitalism&#34;&gt;The problem is capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t think I would get political, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard the anecdote about mattresses or more well known, light bulbs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Capitalism theoretically exists on the basis of supply and demand, where in a perfect existence, a high supply and low demand commodity would be cheap. Unfortunately (or fortunately) for all of us, the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to an Economy textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightbulbs and mattresses were fron conception, both low demand commodity items that are produced very cheaply, and they both respectfully have two different solutions to being low demand items, they are as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned Obsolescence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arbitrarily increase the price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are both methods employed by hardware companies in the modern day. Computers and and the components inside of them can last ~5 years of decent to well usage before ever having to upgrade a component. According to Steam, 5% of PC gamers are &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; using a GPU from 2016. People have only just recently started to upgrade their graphics cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like mattresses, people don&amp;rsquo;t really buy new stock until its a necessity so they increase the profit margins as much as they can get away with, and like lightbulbs, hardware manufacturers have a tendency to &lt;em&gt;force&lt;/em&gt; the hand of their most loyal users via planned obsolescence. The biggest example in recent years has to be Windows 11&amp;rsquo;s TPM 2.0 requirements, which many desktop users, especially in the gaming sphere, did not care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we can view the 1.6 million Windows 7 users in 2012 also as the number of computers laptops, their components, and their accessories thrown into landfills. Very little of what was once a cherished past is properly salvageable, and a lot of it gives credit to the constant advancement in the complexity of software. 64 Megabytes of RAM in 2023 is nowhere as useful as it was in 1998. Hell, an image loaded onto a web browser would easily overtake that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ghost-of-malware-past&#34;&gt;The Ghost of Malware Past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-render-of-the-adware-desktop-assistant-program-bonzi-buddyhttpsuploadwikimediaorgwikipediaen99dbonzi_buddypng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/9/9d/Bonzi_Buddy.png&#34; alt=&#34;A render of the Adware Desktop Assistant program Bonzi Buddy&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit generic to be talking about fucking Bonzi Buddy when referring to malware. I know all about the memes centering around him, but I&amp;rsquo;m talking about him for a good reason. Bonzi Buddy is the perfect dummy to use as an example of malware of the Wild West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonzi Buddy is mostly nonmalicious. The most malicious aspects of Bonzi not comes from intentional designs, but by poor planning. Bonzi Buddy gets called numerous different names. Spyware, Adware, Trojan. All of these are true in the definition sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonzi Buddy works by behaving as an assistant for your computer. Think of it like Siri or Cortana but half as intelligent and twice as annoying. Bonzi Software collected user data to send to their centralized server to sell to advertisers. Stuff like their browsing history was monitored through unwarranted changes to their system, like changing their home page to bonzi.com. If bonzi buddy couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to the bonzi servers, it will store user data on their system, waiting for a reconnection to the central server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can probably assume, this proved disastrous on people&amp;rsquo;s hard drives, most of which didn&amp;rsquo;t break a gigabyte or two. People will browse the internet for hours upon hours, unaware that their hard drives were potentially overwriting key system files for junk userdata, waiting to be sent to Bonzi Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They just simply don&amp;rsquo;t make malware like they used to. (lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;userdata-for-nerds&#34;&gt;Userdata? For nerds!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new concept started in 2009, Cryptocurrency. A decentralized, purely speculative, unmoderated avenue for exchanging currency between hands. For malware developers, this was the dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This created a direct line for people to financially profit from developing malicious software, not saying everybody who used bitcoin did it for malicious purposes. But after the invention of Bitcoin, there was a noticable decrease in the development of Adware and spyware from small groups. Out went Adware, and in came Ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ransomware-and-bitcoin-partners-in-crime&#34;&gt;Ransomware and Bitcoin, Partners in Crime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the growth of Cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum, there had been a drastic increase in the cost of cybercrimes. In 2009 alone, the year Bitcoin was invented, there was an immediate doubling in the cost of cybercrimes, creating an exponential steepness or a parabola from that moment onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/transactionscrypto.png&#34; alt=&#34;A chart showing a timeline for the number of transactions for cryptocurrencies&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/win7/cybercrimechart.png&#34; alt=&#34;A chart showing a timeline for the cost of cybercrimes that have occurred, with the year that Bitcoin was created being marked&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As malware moved away from trojan adware to purely profits, you can see less attempts of malicious software attempting to gain user trust. The wild west of the internet is over, there is now no question what is and what isn&amp;rsquo;t malware anymore. Nondestructive malware is almost as rare as nonmalicious software was back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is a safer place for the average user. Instead of being the target, average users have become collateral damage. The computers running Windows 7 are tools used, typically by Government Backed groups, to spread to more desirable systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-malware&#34;&gt;The Future Of Malware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Malware groups moving towards more profit motives, its only obvious that they will continue to attack where there&amp;rsquo;s money. Average users aren&amp;rsquo;t where the money is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I was to make a guess as to where computing and malware is gonna go in the future, I&amp;rsquo;d wager a bet on a heavier focus on Thin Clients and Cloud-based computing. Chromebooks were a sign for companies like Microsoft that it&amp;rsquo;s a profitable business. The only major downside is that these thinclients would be relying on a server for heavier processes, and those servers would definitely be targets for attacks of all sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you think computers and malware will change with time? &lt;a href=&#34;https://wetdry.world/@ioletsgo/111199759552863724&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chairs and Creating the best environment for you</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-banner-of-a-jack-frost-plushy-sitting-on-a-new-office-chairpostschairbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;A banner of a jack frost plushy sitting on a new office chair&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently got a new chair, and it made me start to think about ergonomics a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/jackfrostchair.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a jack frost plushy sitting on a new office chair&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/oldchair.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of an particularly simple chair, that being the old chair&#34;&gt;
Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s great. The mesh back allows for a lot of airflow, there&amp;rsquo;s fantastic back support, and there&amp;rsquo;s also retractable armrests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something that I got on deal for $30, I think it was more than a good bargain, especially compared to the Wish Chair From Hell that costs around the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there&amp;rsquo;s only one type of chair I think would be worse&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;picture-of-a-chair-marketed-towards-gamerspostschairgamingchairjpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/gamingchair.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a chair marketed towards Gamers&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-chairs-are-not-good&#34;&gt;Gaming chairs are NOT good!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(and here&amp;rsquo;s why)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming chairs, because they take direct inspiration off of racing car seats, or bucket seats, they are designed to preserve a human in the case of a crash.
They are designed to protect against large and sudden G-Forces, not for comfort or even for ergonomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bucket seats are designed so that you would tense up, especially around your shoulders, when mixed with the chest breathing technique, which a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t even know is a terrible way to breath, means that you are making yourself more and more uncomfortable just by sitting on a chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diagram-of-proper-and-improper-breathing-technique-chairs-that-take-inspiration-from-bucket-seats-encourage-improper-breathing-techniques-at-the-benefit-of-preserving-life-in-high-g-force-enviromentspostschairbreathing-diagrampng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/breathing-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;Diagram of proper and improper breathing technique, chairs that take inspiration from bucket seats encourage improper breathing techniques at the benefit of preserving life in high G-force enviroments&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ergonomics-vs-comfort-a-battle-of-frenemies&#34;&gt;Ergonomics VS Comfort, A Battle of Frenemies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth is, I have a ridiculously small desk.
It&amp;rsquo;s dimentions are 31x18.5 inches, and sans an elevated platform at the back, there really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything special about this desk, however what&amp;rsquo;s creativity without restrictions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;deske1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a blank desk with a deskmat, lamp, and mouse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/deske2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An overview of a blank desk with a deskmat, lamp, and mouse&#34;&gt;
With a deskmat, Mechanical Keyboard, some games, maybe a plushy or two, a CD Player, and a bunch of other bits and bops, it really does start to feel like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;picture-of-a-desk-full-of-sentimental-materials-with-a-laptop-pearched-ontop-of-an-elevated-section-in-the-backpostschairdeskjpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/chair/desk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a desk full of sentimental materials with a laptop pearched ontop of an elevated section in the back&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the large space between the mouse and the keyboard. This was intenionally done to prevent Carpal Tunnel, through minimizing as many intersections my arms have to deal with on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position of my laptop is a deliberate choice, as to prevent neckpain. Proper office ergonomics states that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to move your head down to look at your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-diagram-showing-proper-laptopmonitor-placement-to-encourage-the-best-posturehttpswwwgvsueducms4asset30f6d8a1-9140-75c7-2caacf4a83b9d5a8monitor_angle5b14274795425djpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gvsu.edu/cms4/asset/30F6D8A1-9140-75C7-2CAACF4A83B9D5A8/monitor_angle%5B1427479542%5D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A diagram showing proper laptop/monitor placement to encourage the best posture&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elevated platform is simply a convienent alternative to the advised laptop stand in the diagram above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that comfort isn&amp;rsquo;t just a physical state, but a mental state as well. If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable both physically and mentally, you will overall perform better at any task that you set yourself out to complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
