<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <image>
    <url>https://ioletsgo.gay/Assets/they.png</url>
    <title>Favicon for ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <link>https://blog.ioletsgo.gay</link>
  </image>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content from blog.ioletsgo.gay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 22:12:18 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Quest To Learn Programming: Prerequisites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 22:12:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;banner-for-the-quest-to-learn-programming-prerequisitespostsprogrammingbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner for The Quest To Learn Programming: Prerequisites&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my knowledge in computers, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to really sit myself down and learn programming. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it was never out of me not trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by computers, some of my earliest memories involve loading an old Dell laptop with so many viruses it constituted as a threat to national security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give you the whole &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;in 1981 the IBM Personal Computer was invented&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; talk cause, while I think its important, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to parrot the entire history of the personal computer, UNIX systems, DOS, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want an interesting look into the history of computers, I would probably recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@ComputerChroniclesYT&#34;&gt;The Computer Chronicles&lt;/a&gt;, beautifully archived on Youtube by Danooct1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I see it, computers are relatively simple devices that are able to do a lot of complicated maths due to make interesting things happen. While I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to enter from the deep end using x86 Assembly off the bat, I&amp;rsquo;m an inquisitive mind and I have a tendency to ask a lot of questions that leads to &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Well, In x86 assembly...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, which can be both annoying and demotivating if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the necessary resources to ask and get answers for complicated questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;I don&#39;t want to be the type of person that doesn&#39;t understand why or how programming works&lt;/code&gt;, which is why I made an unusual purchase of a programming textbook&amp;ndash; Particularly, the C++ Programming Language 4th Edition Hard Cover by Bjarne Stroustrup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cover-of-the-c-programming-language-fourth-edition-textbookpostsprogrammingcppbookjpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/programming/CPPBook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The cover of the C++ Programming Language Fourth Edition Textbook&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intended goal is to be able to record my journey of using this resource, possibly in hopes to encourage others who are in a very similar position to me, the massive textbook being a constant physical reminder and motivator for me to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s fucking learn I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
