<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <image>
    <url>https://ioletsgo.gay/Assets/they.png</url>
    <title>Favicon for ioletsgo.gay</title>
    <link>https://blog.ioletsgo.gay</link>
  </image>
    <link>http://ioletsgo.gay/tags/desk/</link>
    <description>Recent content from blog.ioletsgo.gay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 09:15:49 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ioletsgo.gay/tags/desk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Laptop Nerd Builds Her First Computer</title>
      <link>http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 09:15:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;banner-for-first-computer-blog-postpostscomputerbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner for First Computer Blog Post&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had my own personal desktop, which may be surprising for those who know me as a tech nerd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous blog post about &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/&#34;&gt;Chairs, Carpal Tunnel Syndrome, and my acute obsession with ergonomics&lt;/a&gt;, You probably noticed the fact that, despite being a tech nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a full tower PC. You can see this as a continuation of that previous blogpost, as a whole load of stuff has changed since then. Honestly I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start&amp;hellip;
So I guess we start where we last left off, with the Desk and what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;audio&#34;&gt;Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-my-desk-with-a-bunch-of-audio-equipment-like-a-microphone-midi-keyboard-and-an-audio-interfacepostscomputermusic1png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/music1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of my desk, with a bunch of audio equipment like a microphone, midi keyboard, and an audio interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last time I&amp;rsquo;ve posted I&amp;rsquo;ve completely overhauled my audio setup. You may not have been able to tell, but in the original setup, I had a Behringer U-Phoria UM2 audio interface that started to get really static-y in the XLR port, almost to the point where the microphone became unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-a-behringer-u-phoria-um2postscomputerimage_be_p0avv_um2_front_xlpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/Image_BE_P0AVV_UM2_Front_XL.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of a Behringer U-Phoria UM2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After believing that its the microphone (and breaking it, I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a project for a later date. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ioletsgo.gay/index.xml#feed&#34;&gt;If that sounds like fun, please subscribe to the RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;), I had to replace my mic (that I bought Used) with a brand new AT2020, and a BluCoil 48 V Portable USB Audio Interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-a-blucoil-48-v-portable-usb-audio-interfacepostscomputerblucoil-portable-usb-audio-interfacewebp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/Blucoil-Portable-USB-Audio-Interface.webp&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of a BluCoil 48 V Portable USB Audio Interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my reasoning for choosing this audio interface was the fact that I wanted something that worked, but also had knobs on the front (My autistic brain absolutely loves physical dials and analog audio controls. Also they look really cool.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headphones I daily drive are the Audio Technica ATH-M50xBT2, costing around 170 dollars on sale. I can highly recommend these headphones for a multitude of reasons, with the battery being an easy sell and the mobile app being a change of pace compared to similar high end devices that makes you feel like you need it to get the least out of your devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-the-audio-technica-ath-m50xbt2-limited-edition-deep-sea-bluepostscomputerath-m50xbt2png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/ATH-M50XBT2.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of the Audio Technica ATH-M50xBT2 Limited Edition Deep Sea Blue&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire purpose of this build was Flexibility. I never, at any point, wanted to feel like I was held back by my hardware choices. If I, say, wanted to make Youtube Videos, I&amp;rsquo;m totally capable of doing that with this audio setup. If I wanted to make music, I have my Midi Keyboard, I have my myriad of musical instruments, and you&amp;rsquo;d better believe I&amp;rsquo;ll be busting some tunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-actual-computer&#34;&gt;The Actual Computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably didn&amp;rsquo;t click on this blog post for audio nerd shit. You clicked on this blog for some old fashioned computer nerd shit. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able satisfy that need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-noir&#34;&gt;The Noir&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-picture-of-the-zalman-z3-iceberg-computer-casepostscomputerz3-icebergpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/Z3-Iceberg.png&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of the Zalman Z3 Iceberg Computer Case&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a Zalman Iceberg computer case, it ensures that this AMD-based system gets plenty of air, creating the best possible environment for my Linux system to operate, and for a cheap price too.
I built her over the span of 3 months, with the best end-of-the-line AM4 hardware possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-pc-part-picker-list-showing-a-high-end-computer-fully-paid-for-going-slightly-over-1600-usdpostscomputerpcpartpickerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/computer/pcpartpicker.png&#34; alt=&#34;A PC part picker list showing a high end computer fully paid for going slightly over 1,600 USD&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She can run basically any software I toss at it. With 32 gigs of ram she&amp;rsquo;s an absolute beast that only the highest end of AAA games with absolutely abysmal optimizations could dream of filling, all while running at a low 40C and only going to high 50Cs under heavy loads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time building a computer was definitely&amp;hellip; Interesting. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I basically had the entire thing built that I had to use my background in tech support to deduce that I got a faulty motherboard (I went all-in on the fact that the computer booted ONCE with no stability issues, even under heavy CPU, GPU, and RAM loads. If anything crashed while it was booted I knew that it was something else.), so I had to get a replacement. While I was swapping all of the components, I accidentally bent one of the pins on my CPU. Just my luck. Luckily I have small steady hands so I was able to bend the pins back with relative ease.
I was too busy focusing on fixing shit that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even think to document it.
Building a computer was definitely a unique experience, multiple points did i lose motivation and almost give up, but I knew that it would all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porting the original blogpost to the new blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this desktop for over 4 months, and its been going really smooth. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any real trouble with it and its given me a lot of freedom to do stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to do. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;d heavily recommend building a computer for anybody who is interested in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chairs and Creating the best environment for you</title>
      <link>http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-banner-of-a-jack-frost-plushy-sitting-on-a-new-office-chairpostschairbannerpng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;A banner of a jack frost plushy sitting on a new office chair&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently got a new chair, and it made me start to think about ergonomics a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/jackfrostchair.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a jack frost plushy sitting on a new office chair&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/oldchair.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of an particularly simple chair, that being the old chair&#34;&gt;
Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s great. The mesh back allows for a lot of airflow, there&amp;rsquo;s fantastic back support, and there&amp;rsquo;s also retractable armrests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something that I got on deal for $30, I think it was more than a good bargain, especially compared to the Wish Chair From Hell that costs around the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there&amp;rsquo;s only one type of chair I think would be worse&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;picture-of-a-chair-marketed-towards-gamerspostschairgamingchairjpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/gamingchair.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a chair marketed towards Gamers&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-chairs-are-not-good&#34;&gt;Gaming chairs are NOT good!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(and here&amp;rsquo;s why)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming chairs, because they take direct inspiration off of racing car seats, or bucket seats, they are designed to preserve a human in the case of a crash.
They are designed to protect against large and sudden G-Forces, not for comfort or even for ergonomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bucket seats are designed so that you would tense up, especially around your shoulders, when mixed with the chest breathing technique, which a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t even know is a terrible way to breath, means that you are making yourself more and more uncomfortable just by sitting on a chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diagram-of-proper-and-improper-breathing-technique-chairs-that-take-inspiration-from-bucket-seats-encourage-improper-breathing-techniques-at-the-benefit-of-preserving-life-in-high-g-force-enviromentspostschairbreathing-diagrampng&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/breathing-diagram.png&#34; alt=&#34;Diagram of proper and improper breathing technique, chairs that take inspiration from bucket seats encourage improper breathing techniques at the benefit of preserving life in high G-force enviroments&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ergonomics-vs-comfort-a-battle-of-frenemies&#34;&gt;Ergonomics VS Comfort, A Battle of Frenemies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth is, I have a ridiculously small desk.
It&amp;rsquo;s dimentions are 31x18.5 inches, and sans an elevated platform at the back, there really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything special about this desk, however what&amp;rsquo;s creativity without restrictions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;deske1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a blank desk with a deskmat, lamp, and mouse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/deske2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An overview of a blank desk with a deskmat, lamp, and mouse&#34;&gt;
With a deskmat, Mechanical Keyboard, some games, maybe a plushy or two, a CD Player, and a bunch of other bits and bops, it really does start to feel like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;picture-of-a-desk-full-of-sentimental-materials-with-a-laptop-pearched-ontop-of-an-elevated-section-in-the-backpostschairdeskjpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ioletsgo.gay/posts/chair/desk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of a desk full of sentimental materials with a laptop pearched ontop of an elevated section in the back&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the large space between the mouse and the keyboard. This was intenionally done to prevent Carpal Tunnel, through minimizing as many intersections my arms have to deal with on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position of my laptop is a deliberate choice, as to prevent neckpain. Proper office ergonomics states that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to move your head down to look at your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-diagram-showing-proper-laptopmonitor-placement-to-encourage-the-best-posturehttpswwwgvsueducms4asset30f6d8a1-9140-75c7-2caacf4a83b9d5a8monitor_angle5b14274795425djpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gvsu.edu/cms4/asset/30F6D8A1-9140-75C7-2CAACF4A83B9D5A8/monitor_angle%5B1427479542%5D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A diagram showing proper laptop/monitor placement to encourage the best posture&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elevated platform is simply a convienent alternative to the advised laptop stand in the diagram above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that comfort isn&amp;rsquo;t just a physical state, but a mental state as well. If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable both physically and mentally, you will overall perform better at any task that you set yourself out to complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
